

Sreemonta Bhowmik

(+88)01710480058 sreemonta.bhowmik@gmail.com

https://github.com/sreemonta20

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sreemonta-bhowmik-92b89320/

https://sreemonta.netlify.app/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly skilled software engineering expert with 10+ years of experience in the software industries. A collaborative developer and engineer with experience and education in the software side of technology who thrives on discovery and accelerating performance.

SKILLS

Languages C# (Fluent), Typescript (Fluent), VB.NET (Competent), JavaScript (Fluent), C++ (Competent)

Frameworks ASP.NET 6.0 (Fluent), Angular 14 (Fluent), Entity Framework Core (Fluent), Express.js (Competent)

Architectures MVC (Fluent), Microservice (Competent)

Databases SQL Server (Fluent), PostgreSQL (Competent), MongoDB (Competent)

Web Dev Platforms .NET 6.0 Web API (Fluent), Ajax (Fluent), Node.js (Competent)

Libraries JQuery (Fluent), React.js (Competent)

Reporting Tools Crystal Report (Fluent), RDLC (Fluent)

Framework Components LINQ

Tools, Technologies & VS 2022, VS Code, Azure Repos (Intermediate), Azure App Service (Intermediate), Docker

Version Controls (Intermediate), **TFS**, **Git**, **Gitlab**, **SVN**, **Visual SourceSafe**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer (Mar 2021 – Present)

M2SYS Technology • Dhaka

- Responsible for requirement analysis, design, development, and API documentation of software solutions for the clients.
- Working on multiple projects (1. Cloud-based Biometric solutions for various industries such as border management, health
 sectors in several countries 2. CloudApper, which is a platform that makes it simple for businesses to create and deploy taskspecific web and mobile apps) on-demand basis.
- Increased the customer satisfaction score from 75% to 95% by providing an alternate solution in Biometric analytics service, which was dependent on the third-party service earlier.
- Successfully completed the development of two Connectors and deployed, which is an intermediary mapper & API platform, which acts between CloudApper and the Client server. It helped at least two targeted customers to agree to do their business with M2SYS.
- Successfully completed the development of Biometric API for biometric operations and internal biometric data migration process.

Software Architect (Mar 2020 - Sep 2020)

LeadSoft Bangladesh Limited • Dhaka

- Collaborating with the various stockholders about the requirements and analyzing the requirements with the development team.
- Designing, architecting, developing the software from the ground level, and creating high-level design documents.
- Guiding, motivating, and assisting the development team (by providing an architectural blueprint) throughout the process and ensuring that all are aligned with development understanding and deadlines.
- Ensuring software security, code refactoring & reviewing on the daily basis, UAT testing, coaching, and training of team members to ensure that all end customers are confident enough to use the software applications.

- Conducting daily SCRUM meetings to remove obstacles in the team toward development and weekly knowledge-sharing meeting on best practices in coding and new technologies.
- Successfully completed the Production Module of Pharmaceutical ERP solution with new technologies on an ASAP basis and helped to generate the revenue of approximately 40% to meet the departmental revenue generation target.
- Successfully migration of old Pharmaceutical ERP solutions with new technologies and tools, which were facing various problems to fit new customers' requirements.

Senior Software Engineer (Oct 2015 - Feb 2020)

Raihana Consulting (A US-based offshore company) • Dhaka

- Lead the application development team to successfully launch multiple applications for multiple clients on time with a number of constraints, while ensuring no compromise to the highest level of quality of standards and meeting customer requirements.
- Overseas and local client communication regarding the new requirements, existing software errors, and bugs.
- Documenting all the applications and support systems, to present clear concepts about the high-level design and business procedures of existing or new applications, effectively training, sharing technical knowledge, and hence reducing the on boarding time by 35%.
- Developed and deployed the user-interactive system successfully, which became the prime product of the company to generate revenue by 50% every year.

Programmer (Jul 2014 - Oct 2015)

CSL Software Resources Limited • Dhaka

- Developed various modules of different ERP web solutions (Accounting, Apparel Manufacturing) along with various reports where database design and modification were done for existing and new applications.
- Achieved a total of 30% (comprising software and support agreement) of the revenue budget of the company by finishing the critical and essential modules of the Accounting ERP solution within the deadline, and deploying.
- The enormous development of the RDLC report and client support, contributed to the increment of the revenue earning by at least 15 to 20% where new approaches to customer data visualization were introduced for successful customer retention.
- Attending weekly knowledge sharing sessions, leading and pairing programming with juniors to make them confident and productive, and reporting to the supervisor about project flow, progression, and technical difficulties.

Programmer (Apr 2012 - Jul 2012)

CSL Software Resources Limited • Dhaka

- Windows-based ERP software and report development for mainly apparel industries.
- A large volume of analysis reports modification and development which helped to enlarge the revenue percentage to more than 15%.
- Involved immediately in effective client communication, satisfying the requirements by developing or modifying the various modules, and on-time delivery results reduced the on-board training cost by 5%.
- Multi-task and change from one task to another without the loss of efficiency or composure where possessed up-to-date technical knowledge which helped to apply the best technical ideas to design the solutions for the end clients.

Junior Programmer (Jun 2010 - Mar 2012)

Raihana Consulting (A US-based offshore company) • Dhaka

- Participated in coding activities, maintaining the integrity of program logic and coding, developing and updating existing systems to increase task success rate by 25%, and eventually increased the annual profit to near about 15 to 20%.
- Worked with senior technology solutions team members to assist with the development of over 2+ software solutions on a wide variety of platforms including web, and Desktop.
- Team collaboration for Microsoft Dynamics customization using AX.

EDUCATION

Master in Applied Mathematics

Jul 2012 - Jun 2014

South Asian University • New Delhi

VOLUNTEER WORK

Senior Software Engineer (Oct 2020 - Feb 2021)

Redeem Tech • Copenhagen

- Developed a Windows-based application and deployed it at the client-side to help to generate revenue of approximately 10% for the startup.
- Team collaboration and assisting team members to achieve the business goal and coding issues for fulfilling the client requirements.
- Research & Development related work was done with the co-worker to understand the business and prepared DFD, Architectural design, and final documents (HLD).